Cloud computing is the on-demand delivery
of IT resources via the internet,
with pay-as-you-go pricing.
Instead of buying, owning and maintaining
physical data centers and servers
you can access technology services,
such as computing power, storage and databases,
on an as-needed basis from a cloud provider
like Amazon Web Services.
Organizations of every type, size and industry
are using the cloud for a wide variety of use cases,
such as data backup, disaster recovery,
email, virtual desktops,
software development and testing,
big data analytics,
and customer facing web applications.
For example, health care companies
are using the cloud to develop
more personalized treatments for patients.
Financial services companies
are using the cloud to power
real-time fraud detection and prevention.
And video game makers are using the cloud
to deliver online games to millions of players
around the world.
With cloud computing your business
can become more agile,
reduce costs, instantly scale,
and deploy globally in minutes.
Cloud computing gives you instance access
to a broad range of technologies
so you can innovate faster
and build nearly anything you can imagine,
from infrastructure services
such as compute, storage and databases,
to Internet of Things, machine learning,
data analytics, and much more.
You can deploy technology services
in a matter of minutes
and get from idea to implementation
several orders of magnitude faster than before.
This gives you the freedom to experiment
and test new ideas to differentiate
customer experiences and transform your business,
such as adding machine learning
and intelligence to your applications
in order to personalize experiences
for your customers and improve their engagement.
You don't need to make large,
upfront investments in hardware
and overpay for capacity you don't use.
Instead you can trade capital expense
for variable expense
and only pay for IT as you consume it.
With cloud computing you access resources
from the cloud in real time as they're needed.
You can scale these resources up and down
to grow or shrink capacity instantly
as your business needs change.
Cloud computing also makes it easy to expand
to new regions and deploy globally in minutes.
For example, Amazon Web Services
has infrastructure all over the world
so you're able to deploy your application
in multiple physical locations in just a few clicks.
Putting applications in closer proximity
to end users reduces latency
and improves their experience.
No matter your location, size or industry,
the cloud frees you from managing infrastructure
and data centers so you can focus
on what matter most to your business.